Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul B. Henze papers
1856-2010
2005C42
Hoover Institution Archives
263 manuscript boxes, 1 oversized box (110.8 linear feet)
The Paul B. Henze papers consist of diaries, writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, research materials, printed matter, and photographs relating to Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty broadcasting to Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union; conditions in Eastern Europe, the Soviet Union and the former Soviet Union, especially the Caucasus and Central Asia; and conditions in Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa. The papers include publications of Radio Free Europe, Radio Liberty, and related organizations, as well as research materials for the numerous books and articles written by Henze, particularly The Plot to Kill the Pope (New York, 1983).
Henze, Paul B.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives between 2005 and 2014.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Claire Sterling papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Eritrean subject collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Ethiopian Subject collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Radio Free Europe corporate records, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1924 August 29 Born, Redwood Falls, Minnesota
1942-1943 Studied at St. Olaf College, Northfield, Minnesota
1943 Enlisted in the United States Army
1944 September-1945 November Served in U.S. Military Government detachment I4G2, based primarily in Monschau, Germany
1948 BA, St. Olaf College, Northfield, Minnesota
1950 MA, Soviet Studies, Harvard University
1950 June 21 Began work at the Central Intelligence Agency
1951 September 15 Married Martha Elaine Heck
1952 November-1958 April Deputy Political Advisor, Radio Free Europe, Munich, Germany
1958-1959 Communications advisor, Turkey
1960-1961 Research staff, Johns Hopkins University
1961-1968 Executive, U.S. Department of Defense
1969-1972 1st secretary, U.S. Embassy in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
1972 Received Order of Menelik from Haile Selassie of Ethiopia
1973 Department of State, Washington, D.C.
1974-1977 1st Secretary, U.S. Embassy in Ankara, Turkey
1977 Author, Ethiopian Journeys: Travels in Ethiopia, 1969-72
1977-1980 National Security Council staff
1980 December Retired from government service
1981 Author, Turkey, the Alliance and the Middle East: Problems and Opportunities in Historical Perspective
1981-1982 Wilson Fellow, Smithsonian Institution
1982-2002 Resident Consultant, RAND corporation
1983 Author, The Plot to Kill the Pope
1991 Author, The Horn of Africa: From War to Peace
1992 Headed International Alert missions to Chechnia and Georgia
2000 Author, Layers of Time: A History of Ethiopia
2001 Author, Eritrea's War: Confrontation, International Response, Outcome, Prospects
2007 Author, Ethiopia in Mengistu's Final Years
2011 May 19 Died, Culpeper, Virginia
Scope and Content of Collection
The Paul B. Henze papers consist of diaries, writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, reports, research materials, printed matter, and photographs relating to Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty broadcasting to Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union; conditions in Eastern Europe, the Soviet Union and the former Soviet Union, especially the Caucasus and Central Asia; and conditions in Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa. The papers include publications of Radio Free Europe, Radio Liberty, and related organizations, as well as research materials for the numerous books and articles written by Henze, particularly The Plot to Kill the Pope (New York, 1983).
In 1952, Paul B. Henze, a World War II veteran and recent Harvard graduate in Soviet studies, moved to Munich to serve as Radio Free Europe's deputy political advisor. For nearly six years, Henze worked closely with William E. Griffith, RFE's chief political advisor, to shape the policies and programs of the growing radio station. Correspondence, memoranda, guidances, and reports from these early years can be found in the Radio Free Europe file. Of particular interest are files documenting RFE's conduct during the 1956 Hungarian uprising, flyers from balloon campaigns in Czechoslovakia, and reports on Polish defectors. In addition to writing policy and background reports, Henze traveled frequently to negotiate the construction of an RFE transmitter site outside Istanbul. Documents from this failed attempt can be found in the Chronological subseries.
Although Henze left Radio Free Europe in 1958 for a position in Turkey, his interest in the organization continued throughout his life. In the 1960s, Henze was involved in the Radio Study Group, a CIA-led project to assess the funding and future of RFE. Some of the research materials in the Radio Free Europe file were assembled for this initiative. Later, while on staff at the National Security Council during the Carter Administration, Henze served as a liaison between the White House and the Board for International Broadcasting. Files from this period chronicle efforts to move the headquarters of RFE from Munich to the United States. After retiring from government service, Henze continued to write and lecture on the history of RFE, as reflected in his speeches and writings.
In his 30 years of government service, Henze held high-level positions in Turkey, Ethiopia, and Carter's White House. Aside from National Security Council documents related to Radio Free Europe, Henze's papers do not include working files from these postings. After retiring from public service in December 1980, Henze began to research and write extensively on subjects that were formerly under his purview as a government employee, such as the Horn of Africa and the non-Russian nationalities of the Soviet Union. His research and writings, as received by the Archives, were grouped by these subjects, and can be found in the Horn of Africa, Caucasus and Central Asia files.
While employed by the RAND Corporation, Henze became famous for his book The Plot to Kill the Pope, which, along with the work of Claire Sterling, popularized the "Bulgarian connection" in the 1981 assassination attempt against Pope John Paul II. In his book, related articles, television appearances, and film scripts, all of which are located in The Plot to Kill the Pope file, Henze sought to show that that Soviet Union was behind the actions of Mehmet Ali Ağca.
Although Henze grouped his papers, including the bulk of his correspondence, by his research interests, he kept a separate file of extensive personal letters with friends such William Griffith, Richard Pankhurst, and Ralph Walter, which can be found in the Correspondence series. Items in his Biographical file, such as an application to work at Radio Free Europe and photographs of his wife and children, comprise some of the earliest items in the collection.
A productive writer from an early age, Henze began keeping detailed diaries while a soldier and later as a military government official in Germany from 1944-1945. Henze's World War II diaries formed the basis for his undergraduate thesis and provide a glimpse into the daily life of an American soldier during the occupation of Germany.
John Paul II, Pope, 1920-2005--Assassination attempt, 1981.; Radio Free Europe.; Radio Liberty.; Asia, Central.; Caucasus, South.; Ethiopia--History.; Ethiopia--Politics and government.; Europe, Eastern.; Former Soviet republics.; Radio broadcasting--Europe, Eastern.; Radio broadcasting--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union.; United States--Defenses.; United States--Foreign relations--1977-1981.; United States--Military policy.
- Biographical File, 1952-2009 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains notes, biographical sketches, certificates, clippings, and photographs.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by physical form and thereunder chronologically.
  - Address books and notes, 1986 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Application for employment at the National Committee for a Free Europe, 1952 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Biographical sketches, 1986, 1998 (Box-folder 1: 3-4)
  - Certificates, 1971, 1992
    - United States Military Advisory Group to Ethiopia, 1971 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Society of Friends of the Institute of Ethiopian Studies, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Clippings, 1953-1991
    - 1953-1979 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1986-1990 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Google search results for Paul Henze, 2006 March 22 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Hunting license, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Photographs, 1950s-2006
    - Paul and Martha Henze with children, 1950s (Box-folder 1: 12-14)
      Includes negatives, proof sheets and prints.
    - Paul Henze and an unidentified man in an office, 1970s (Box-folder 1: 15)
      2" negatives.
    - Two portraits of Paul Henze in Ethiopia, circa 1980 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Paul Henze's house outside of Bethesda, Maryland, 2002 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Paul Henze's 80th birthday party, 2004 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 2002-2006, undated (Box-folder 1: 19)
      Subjects include Mitiku Haile, Stuart Munro-Hay, Irma Taddia, Zewde Gabre-Sellassie, and a panel on Radio Free Europe at the Hoover Institution.
  - Program for the American Community School graduation, Ethiopia, 1972 June 2 (Box-folder 1: 20)
- Correspondence File, 1944-2009 (Box 2-6)
  Contains letters, postcards, clippings, and a lecture.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Bennigsen, Alexandre, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Bernard, Noel, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1965-2009 (Box-folder 2: 3-39)
    Includes clippings of Brzezinski's articles.
  - Cioranescu, George, 1979 (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Galantière, Lewis, 1957-1975 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Griffith, William E., 1944-1998 (Box-folder 3: 2-16, Folder 4: 1-4)
  - Halperin, Ernst, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Langendorf, Ernst, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Lemercier-Quelquejay, Chantal, 1986 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Nowak, Jan, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Pankhurst, Richard, 1974-2009 (Box-folder 4: 9-15)
  - Problems of Communism, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Seton-Watson, Hugh and Mary, 1958-1996 (Box-folder 5: 1-8)
    Includes lecture transcript.
  - Spencer, Diana, 1995-2007 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Walter, Ralph E., 1951-2003 (Box-folder 5: 10-18, Box-folder 6: 1-4)
  - Wimbush, S. Enders, 1992-2009 (Box-folder 6: 5-8)
  - Wohlstetter, Albert J. and Roberta, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 6: 9-16)
- World War II Diaries, 1944-1948, 2005 (Box 7-10)
  Contains diaries, transcriptions, notes, and an undergraduate thesis.
  - Introduction to diaries by Henze, 2005 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Diaries in Gregg shorthand, 1944-1945
    - 1944
      - March (Box-folder 7: 2)
      - April 24-May 7 (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - May 7-23 (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - May 15-29 (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - May 24-June 6 (Box-folder 7: 6)
      - June 1-25 (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - June 26-July 31 (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - August 1-17 (Box-folder 7: 9)
      - August 13-17 (Box-folder 7: 10)
      - August 17-29 (Box-folder 7: 11)
      - August 30-September 23 (Box-folder 7: 12)
      - October 13-28 (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - October 23-November 1 (Box-folder 7: 14)
      - November 2-11 (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - November 12-20 (Box-folder 7: 16)
      - November 20-December 1 (Box-folder 7: 17)
      - November 24-1945 March 14 (Box-folder 7: 18)
      - December 11-1945 January 3 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    - 1945
      - January 9-February 15 (Box-folder 7: 20)
      - February 16-March 10 (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - March 15-April 13 (Box-folder 8: 2)
      - April 15-May 18 (Box-folder 8: 3)
      - May 19-June 17 (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - June 19-July 10 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - July 11-August 2 (Box-folder 8: 6)
      - August 4-11 (Box-folder 8: 7)
      - August 21-September 4 (Box-folder 8: 8)
      - September 5-22 (Box-folder 8: 9)
      - September 23-October 4 (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - October 7-12 (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - October 13-23 (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - October 28-31 (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - November 1-14 (Box-folder 8: 14)
      - November 15-December 1 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Diary transcriptions, 1944-1945
    Includes annotations and marginalia by Ralph C. Most and William Gaines.
    - 1944 (Box-folder 9: 1-9)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 9: 10-21)
    - "Secret History of Detachment I4G2-H76,", 1944-1945 (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - "A History of the American Occupation of Landkreis Monschau, September 1944-May 1945," St. Olaf College honors thesis, 1948 (Box-folder 10: 1-5)
- Radio Free Europe File, 1951-2004 (Box 11-38)
  Contains guidances, memoranda, reports, correspondence, press surveys, clippings, conference files, broadcast schedules, printed matter, and speeches and writings.
  Arranged in subseries by career or physical form, then alphabetically and thereunder chronologically.
  - Office of the Political Advisor file, 1951-1967
    - Chronological file, 1953-1958
      Contains correspondence, daily logs, charts, notes and reports. Maintained in Henze's original annual files.
      - 1952 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
        Includes an organizational chart of Radio Free Europe.
      - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 11: 5-18)
        Relates mainly to the failed attempt to build an RFE transmitter site in Turkey.
      - 1956 (Box-folder 11: 19)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 12: 1-2)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 12: 3-4)
    - Guidances, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 12: 5-12)
      Relates to Poland, Rudolf Slánský, Joseph Stalin, Georgia, Hungary, Bulgaria, Romania, Ukraine, L.P. Beria, Czechoslovakia, Nikita Khrushchev, and China.
    - Memoranda, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 12: 13-18)
      Relates to program evaluation, personnel issues, policy, translation, and the Czechoslavak, Polish and Hungarian newsrooms. Includes "RFE: Four Essential Ingredients of Its Success" by William E. Griffith, chief political advisor.
    - Photographs, 1953 and undated (Box-folder 12: 19)
      Includes one photograph of RFE employees hired from New York and three photographs of Paul Henze at RFE headquarters in Munich.
    - Background information reports, 1953-1967
      - Bound reports by subject, 1953-1967
        In alphabetical order by volume title.
        - Agricultural handbook, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 13: 1)
        - Agriculture, 1953 March-1955 June (Box-folder 13: 2)
        - Articles, lectures and consultants' papers, 1953 February-1955 June (Box-folder 13: 3)
          Includes papers by Boris Nicolaevsky, Bertram Wolfe and Hugh Seton-Watson.
        - Caucasus and Central Asia, 1952 May-1955 June (Box-folder 13: 4)
        - Chronological series, 1955-1958, 1967
          - 1955 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
          - 1956 (Box-folder 14: 3, Box-folder 15: 1-3)
          - 1957 (Box-folder 16: 1-2, Box-folder 17: 1-2)
          - 1958 (Box-folder 18: 1)
          - 1967 (Box-folder 18: 2)
        - Communist Party I, 1953 May-1955 June (Box-folder 18: 3)
        - Communist Party II, 1954 September-1955 May (Box-folder 19: 1)
        - Communist Party III, 1953 May-1955 June (Box-folder 19: 2)
        - Eastern Europe, 1953 June-1955 June (Box-folder 19: 3)
        - Economics, 1953-June 1955 (Box-folder 19: 4)
        - Far East, 1953 May-1955 June (Box-folder 20: 1)
        - Miscellaneous, 1953 February-1955 June (Box-folder 20: 2)
        - Religion, 1953 July-1955 June (Box-folder 20: 3)
        - Soviet culture and social conditions, 1953 June-1955 June (Box-folder 20: 4)
      - Loose reports by year, 1955-1961 (Folder 21-23)
    - Press surveys, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 24: 1-8)
      Consists of translations from foreign press, primarily from West Germany and Poland.
  - National Security Council file, 1977-1982
    Memoranda, correspondence, reports, and clippings from Henze's tenure as the National Security Council liaison to the Board for International Broadcasting.
    - 1977-1979 (Box-folder 25: 1-18)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 25: 19-26, Box-folder 26: 1-13)
      Includes materials relating to relocating RFE's headquarters from Munich to the United States.
    - 1981 (Box-folder 26: 14)
      Includes materials related to the February 21 bombing of RFE's Munich headquarters.
    - 1982 (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - Speeches and writings, 1954-2004
    - "The Strategic Significance of Recent Events in Tibet,", 1953 (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - "The Mood of Eastern Europe,", 1953 June 30 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - "Agricultural Collectivization in Communist China,", 1954 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - "The New Course and Its Aims,", 1954 (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - "Recent Developments in Eastern Europe," lecture at the NATO Defense College, Paris, 1956 December 14 (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - "Radio Free Europe," St. Olaf Alumni Magazine, 1957 (Box-folder 27: 6)
    - "Some Considerations in Regard to 'National Communism,'", 1957 March 19 (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - "'Un-Rewriting' History: The Shamil Problem,", 1958 (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - "The Decade Ahead: Eastern Europe,", 1960 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    - "Eastern Europe: Sickness and Hope," lecture at Ball State University, 1986 (Box-folder 27: 10)
    - "The Beginnings of Radio Free Europe,", 1996 September 27 (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - "Radio Free Europe's Early Years,", 2004 (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - Henze's collected writings on RFE, 1956-2004 (Box-folder 27: 13)
      Assembled by the author. Includes compact disk.
  - Speeches and writings by others, 1950-1970
    - Galantière, Lewis, 1962 (Box-folder 27: 14)
    - Griffith, William E., 1959-1970 (Box-folder 27: 15-20)
    - Henze, John and Elizabeth, 1963 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    - Henze, Martha, 1953 (Box-folder 28: 2)
      Describes a trip to Yugoslavia in 1953.
    - Johnson, A. Ross, 1999 (Box-folder 28: 3)
    - Pool, Ithiel de Sola, 1965 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - Ritvo, Herbert, 1963 (Box-folder 28: 5)
    - Seton-Watson, Hugh, 1960 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    - Siepmann, Charles A., 1955 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - Wraga, Richard, 1950 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Conference files, 1950s-2004
    - "Radio Propaganda as an Instrument of Anti-Bolshevik Struggle," Institute for the Study of the USSR, 1950s (Box-folder 28: 9)
    - "Conference on Soviet Ethnic Minorities," Brandeis University, 1970s (Box-folder 28: 10)
    - "The Democratic Revolution," National Endowment of Democracy, 1989 May 1-2 (Box-folder 28: 11)
    - "The Failure of Communism and the Western Response," Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty Fund, 1989 November 15 (Box-folder 28: 12)
    - "The Social Legacy of Communism," George Washington University, 1992 February 20-22 (Box-folder 28: 13)
    - "Hungary and the World, 1956," Budapest, 1996 September 26-29 (Box-folder 28: 14-15)
    - "Cold War Broadcasting Impact Conference," Stanford University, 2004 (Box-folder 28: 16)
  - Reports and broadcast schedules, 1950-1988
    - Board for International Broadcasting, 1975-1988 (Box-folder 29: 1-3)
    - Congressional Research Service, 1972 (Box-folder 29: 4)
    - Free Europe Committee, 1950, 1955 (Box-folder 29: 5)
    - Presidential Study Commission on International Radio Broadcasting, 1973 (Box-folder 29: 6)
    - Radio Free Europe audience research reports, 1958-1959, 1965-1966, 1978, 1985 (Box-folder 29: 7-9, Box-folder 30: 1-10)
    - Radio Free Europe broadcast schedules, 1965 (Box-folder 30: 11-12)
  - Research materials, 1951-2002
    The bulk of the material was assembled by Henze for the Radio Study Group and later writings on Radio Free Europe.
    - Abakumov, Viktor Semenovich, 1954 (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - Afghanistan, 1980 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - American Committee for Liberation from Bolshevism, 1953 (Box-folder 31: 3)
    - American Committee for Liberation, 1961 (Box-folder 31: 4)
    - Antropov, Petr Iakovlevich, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 5)
    - Arab nationalism, 1971 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Azerbaijan, 1966 (Box-folder 31: 7)
    - Balloon operations, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 31: 8-12)
      Relates primarily to activities in Czechoslovakia. Includes flyers from Operation Prospero.
    - Bitterman, Mary, 1980 (Box-folder 31: 13)
    - Bombing at RFE, 1981 (Box-folder 31: 14)
    - Brezhnev, Leonid Il'ich, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 15)
    - Broadcasting to the Soviet Union, 1966-1980 (Box-folder 31: 16-17)
    - Bulgaria, 1953 (Box-folder 31: 18)
    - Captive Nations Committee, 1983 (Box-folder 31: 19)
    - Central Asia, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 31: 20-21)
    - China, 1954 (Box-folder 31: 22)
    - Cold War, 1972-2000 (Box-folder 31: 23-24)
    - Cuba, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 25)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1968 (Box-folder 31: 26)
    - East Germany, 1965 (Box-folder 31: 27)
    - Hungary, 1952-1996
      - Memoranda, 1953-1957
        - Guidances by Simon Bourgin, 1951 (Box-folder 32: 1)
        - On reorganization of RFE's Hungarian Desk, 1953, 1956 (Box-folder 32: 2-3)
        - Guidances, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 32: 4-5)
      - Reports and lectures, 1952-1996
        - Lecture by William T. Rafael to editors of the Hungarian Desk, 1952 March 21 (Box-folder 32: 6)
        - Hungarian program reports, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 32: 7)
        - Lectures on Hungary by Simon Bourgin, 1956 (Box-folder 32: 8)
        - "Daily Analysis of Events in Hungary,", 1956 October-November (Box-folder 32: 9)
        - Policy review of Voice of Free Hungary programming, 1956 October-November (Box-folder 32: 10)
        - "Challenge and response in Hungary," by Paul Henze, 1956 November (Box-folder 32: 11)
        - "Impressions of Budapest,", 1956 November 8 (Box-folder 32: 12)
        - "Radio Free Europe and the Hungarian Tragedy," by Jan Nowak, 1969 (Box-folder 32: 13)
        - Eyewitness account of Radio Budapest, 1973 (Box-folder 32: 14)
        - "Recollections of Radio Free Europe: Its evolution in the 1950s and the Hungarian Revolution," by Paul Henze, 1980s (Box-folder 32: 15)
        - "The 1956 Hungarian Revolution: Soviet Policy Reassessed," paper by Martin Swartz, 1985 June 7 (Box-folder 32: 16-17)
        - "Hungary and the World, 1956: The New Archival Evidence," Hungary and the World Conference, Budapest, 1996 September 26-29 (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - Interview of Paul Henze by Martin Swartz on Hungary, 1986 (Box-folder 33: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - Printed matter, 1956 (Box-folder 33: 4)
      - Clippings, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 33: 5-6)
    - Iran, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    - Islam, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 33: 8)
    - Jamming (radio signals), 1965-1970s (Box-folder 33: 9-13)
    - Joint Baltic American National Committee, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 14)
    - Kazakhstan, 1993 (Box-folder 33: 15)
    - Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1964 (Box-folder 33: 16)
    - Labedz, Leopold, 1993 (Box-folder 33: 17)
    - Markov, Georgi, 1979 (Box-folder 33: 18)
    - Marsh, William M., 1996 (Box-folder 33: 19)
    - Mass media, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 33: 20)
    - National communism, 1957 (Box-folder 33: 21)
    - National Committee for a Free Europe, 1952 August-October (Box-folder 33: 22-24)
    - Nowak, Jan, 1951-2004 (Box-folder 33: 25-29)